<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ExecutableTestSuite xmlns="http://www.interactive-instruments.de/etf/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="EID0fc46305-c623-422b-b7d7-251c3b86eb7f" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.interactive-instruments.de/etf/2.0 https://resources.etf-validator.net/schema/v2/val/ignoreRef.xsd">
	<itemHash>bQ==</itemHash>
	<remoteResource>http://github.com/inspire-eu-validation/ets-repository/data-gn/gn-as</remoteResource>
	<localPath>/auto</localPath>
	<label>Conformance class: Application schema, Geographical Names</label>
	<description><![CDATA[This test suite examines requirements associated with the application schema.<br/><br/>
<b>This is a draft version. It has limitations and is expected to contain errors.</b> Please report any issues or problems <a href="https://github.com/interactive-instruments/ets-repository/issues" target="_blank">in GitHub</a>.<br/><br/>
Known limitations are documented in the description of the applicable test case or test assertion. There is a general limitation in all assertions that extensions in additional application schemas are only supported, if the unqualified name of the feature type in the extension is the same as the name of the feature type in the INSPIRE application schema.<br/><br/>
Source: <a href="http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/id/ats/data-gn/3.1/gn-as" target="_blank">Conformance Class 'Application schema, Geographical Names'</a><br/><br/>
Pre-requisite conformance classes:
<ul><li><a href="http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/id/ats/data-gn/3.1/gn-gml" target="_blank">Conformance Class 'GML application schemas, Geographical Names'</a></li></ul>]]></description>
	<reference>../../inspire-noggeo-bsxets.xq</reference>
	<version>0.2.1</version>
	<author>PwC</author>
	<creationDate>2016-10-12T00:00:00Z</creationDate>
	<lastEditor>interactive instruments GmbH</lastEditor>
	<lastUpdateDate>2017-05-16T13:00:00Z</lastUpdateDate>
	<tags>
		<tag ref="EID589db923-b4c4-4979-b618-a84ea3228df4"/>
	</tags>
	<testDriver ref="EID4dddc9e2-1b21-40b7-af70-6a2d156ad130"/>
	<translationTemplateBundle ref="EID70a263c0-0ad7-42f2-9d4d-0d8a4ca71b52"/>
	<ParameterList name="ETF Standard Parameters for XML test objects">
		<parameter name="files_to_test" required="true">
			<defaultValue>.*</defaultValue>
			<description ref="TR.filesToTest"/>
			<allowedValues>.*</allowedValues>
			<type>string</type>
		</parameter>
		<parameter name="tests_to_execute" required="false">
			<defaultValue>.*</defaultValue>
			<description ref="TR.testsToExecute"/>
			<allowedValues>.*</allowedValues>
			<type>string</type>
		</parameter>
	</ParameterList>
	<supportedTestObjectTypes>
		<testObjectType ref="EIDe1d4a306-7a78-4a3b-ae2d-cf5f0810853e"/>
	</supportedTestObjectTypes>
	<dependencies>
		<executableTestSuite ref="EID02b7b0cb-429a-4f4e-b0db-988464fb9496"/>
	</dependencies>	
	<testModules>
		<TestModule id="EID016647ff-8d0d-4f8c-a814-0dcd6bcfcb1a">
			<label>IGNORE</label>
			<description>IGNORE</description>
			<parent ref="EID0fc46305-c623-422b-b7d7-251c3b86eb7f"/>
			<testCases>
				<TestCase id="EID38588ffb-072c-4538-901b-563a451b06ef">
					<label>Code list values</label>
					<description>Verify whether all attributes whose value type is a code list take the values set out therein.</description>
					<parent ref="EID016647ff-8d0d-4f8c-a814-0dcd6bcfcb1a"/>
					<testSteps>
						<TestStep id="EIDda0eddd6-416d-41d8-a7ab-5f3b2e9b57dc">
							<label>IGNORE</label>
							<description>IGNORE</description>
							<parent ref="EID38588ffb-072c-4538-901b-563a451b06ef"/>
							<statementForExecution>not applicable</statementForExecution>
							<testItemType ref="EIDf483e8e8-06b9-4900-ab36-adad0d7f22f0"/>
							<testAssertions>
								<TestAssertion id="EID859b1ebb-9e3e-45dd-888b-effd5c692522">
									<label>gn-as.a.1: NamedPlaceType attributes</label>
									<description><![CDATA[When an attribute has a code list as its type, verify that the values comply with the definitions and include the values set out in Annex II of the regulation. For this attribute, the allowed values are specified in code list <a href='http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/codelist/NamedPlaceTypeValue'>http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/codelist/NamedPlaceTypeValue</a>.<br/>For datasets using version 3 of the GML application schema, the value is the last path element of the code list value URI and it is in the child text node. For datasets using version 4 of the GML application schema, the value is in the xlink:href XML attribute and is the HTTP URI of the code list value.<br/><br/>
Relevant requirements:
<ul>
<li>IR Requirement Article 4 (1): Types for the Exchange and Classification of Spatial Objects.  For the exchange and classification of spatial objects from data sets meeting the conditions laid down in Article 4 of Directive 2007/2/EC, Member States shall use the spatial object types and associated data types, enumerations and code lists that are defined in Annexes II, III and IV for the themes the data sets relate to.</li>
<li>IR Requirement Article 4 (3): Types for the Exchange and Classification of Spatial Objects. The enumerations and code lists used in attributes or association roles of spatial object types or data types shall comply with the definitions and include the values set out in Annex II. The enumeration and code list values are uniquely identified by language-neutral mnemonic codes for computers. The values may also include a language-specific name to be used for human interaction.</li>
<li>IR Requirement Article 6 (1): Code Lists and Enumerations. Codelists shall be of one of the following types, as specified in the Annexes:
<ol>
<li>code lists whose allowed values comprise only the values specified in this Regulation;</li>
<li>code lists whose allowed values comprise the values specified in this Regulation and
narrower values defined by data providers;</li>
<li>code lists whose allowed values comprise the values specified in this Regulation and
additional values at any level defined by data providers;</li>
<li>code lists, whose allowed values comprise any values defined by data providers.</li>
</ol>
For the purposes of points 2, 3 and 4, in addition to the allowed values, data providers may use the values specified in the relevant INSPIRE Technical Guidance document available on the INSPIRE web site of the Joint Research Centre.</li>
<li>IR Requirement Article 6 (2): Code Lists and Enumerations. Code lists may be hierarchical. Values of hierarchical code lists may have a more generic parent value. Where the valid values of a hierarchical code list are specified in a table in this Regulation, the parent values are listed in the last column.</li>
<li>IR Requirement Article 6 (3): Code Lists and Enumerations. Where, for an attribute whose type is a code list as referred to in points 2, 3 or 4 of paragraph 1, a data provider provides a value that is not specified in this Regulation, that value and its definition shall be made available in a register.</li>
<li>IR Requirement Article 6 (4): Code Lists and Enumerations. Attributes or association roles of spatial object types or data types whose type is a code list may only take values that are allowed according to the specification of the code list.</li>
</ul>
Source: <a href="http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/id/ats/data-gn/3.1/gn-as/code-list-values" target="_blank">Abstract Test Case 'Code list values'</a>, <a href="http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/documents/Data_Specifications/INSPIRE_DataSpecification_GN_v3.1.pdf">INSPIRE Data Specification on Geographical Names, A.1.3</a>]]></description>
									<parent ref="EIDda0eddd6-416d-41d8-a7ab-5f3b2e9b57dc"/>
									<expectedResult>NOT_APPLICABLE</expectedResult>
									<expression>
let $features3 := $features[self::gn3:NamedPlace]
let $features4 := $features[self::gn:NamedPlace]
let $messages := local:check-code-list-values($features3, $features4, 'type', 'http://inspire.ec.europa.eu/codelist/NamedPlaceTypeValue')
return (if ($messages) then 'FAILED' else 'PASSED', $messages)
									</expression>
									<testItemType ref="EIDf0edc596-49d2-48d6-a1a1-1ac581dcde0a"/>
									<translationTemplates>
										<translationTemplate ref="TR.disallowedCodeListValue"/>
										<translationTemplate ref="TR.featuresWithErrors"/>
									</translationTemplates>
								</TestAssertion>																
							</testAssertions>
						</TestStep>
					</testSteps>
				</TestCase>
				<TestCase id="EIDc31e09f2-f035-4c03-ad67-fd24a39d369d">
					<label>Constraints</label>
					<description>Verify that the features provided in the dataset adhere to the constraints specified in the INSPIRE application schema. Currently none exists for this application schema, so this is a placeholder.</description>
					<parent ref="EID016647ff-8d0d-4f8c-a814-0dcd6bcfcb1a"/>
					<testSteps>
						<TestStep id="EIDb864c646-ec17-4753-b076-8ece4061b621">
							<label>IGNORE</label>
							<description>IGNORE</description>
							<parent ref="EIDc31e09f2-f035-4c03-ad67-fd24a39d369d"/>
							<statementForExecution>not applicable</statementForExecution>
							<testItemType ref="EIDf483e8e8-06b9-4900-ab36-adad0d7f22f0"/>
							<testAssertions>
								<TestAssertion id="EID6093bfc2-5e1e-48cf-9a56-6d3594b5b06f">
									<label>gn-as.b.1: Test always passes</label>
									<description>This conformance class includes no constraints beyond the ones referenced by dependencies, i.e. those that apply across the data themes. This assertion will always pass and is included for technical reasons.</description>
									<parent ref="EIDb864c646-ec17-4753-b076-8ece4061b621"/>
									<expectedResult>NOT_APPLICABLE</expectedResult>
									<expression>'PASSED'</expression>
									<testItemType ref="EIDf0edc596-49d2-48d6-a1a1-1ac581dcde0a"/>
								</TestAssertion>
							</testAssertions>
						</TestStep>
					</testSteps>
				</TestCase>
			</testCases>
		</TestModule>
	</testModules>
</ExecutableTestSuite>
